Mss.B.B28.w Mss.B.B28.w
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to John Bartram, Undated; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:84. Darlington's Memorials 183.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 29, 1751; Dobbs, Arthur, 1689-1765
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:101.
  - Letter to Ann and John Bartram, Jan. 11, 1753; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.302.) Refers to "B.Franklin's Experiment" and electricity. Printed in part: Darlington, pp.188-189.
  - Letter to Jared Eliot, Feb. 12, 1753; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.303.) Refers to "our good friend Benjamin". Printed in part: Darlington, pp.372-373.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 13, 1753; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 6p. Bartram Papers 2:88,89. Darlington's Memorials 190
  - Letter to Charles Linnaeus, March 20, 1753; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.311.) ---Draft, p.310. Refers to Franklin. Printed: Darlington, p.371.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Aug. 20, 1753; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.312-313.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 193-194.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Undated; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:33. Darlington's Memorials 194.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Aug. 21, 1753; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:91.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Aug. 20, 1753; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:35:16.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1753?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Journal of Trip to Kattskills with Billy, 1753; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 11p. Bartram Papers 1:35:1-9. Darlington's Memorials 194.
  - Description of native trees, 1753; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 41 p. Bartram Papers 1:32:1, 1:41:1-14.
  - Letter to Charles Linnaeus, 1753?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:36:2. Darlington's Memorials 371.
  - Letter to Charles Linnaeus, Nov. 11, 1753; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, March 10, 1754; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p Bartram Papers 1:33:4. Darlington's Memorials 195.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 3, 1754; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:37. Darlington's Memorials 196.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, March 1755; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:35:17. Darlington's Memorials 197.
  - Letter to Philip Miller, April 20, 1755; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:35:21. Darlington's Memorials 376
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, April 27, 1755; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 6p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.378-383.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 198-200.
  - Description of Braddock's defeat, July 10, 1755; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:34:2.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Sept. 28, 1755; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 4p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.384-387.) Refers to "Benjamin" [Franklin?]. Printed in part: Darlington, 200-201.
  - Letter to Dr. Garden, Oct. 12, 1755; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:47:11. Darlington's Memorials 390.
  - Letter to Philip Miller, 1755?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:29. Peter Collinson's notes on specimens sent.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 14, 1756?; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:102.
  - Linnaean Society of London, 1755; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 2, 1756; Miller, Philip, 1691-1771
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:79. Darlington's Memorials 378.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 10, 1756; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    London, Typed L. 4p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.402-405.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 203-204.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 18, 1756; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed L. 4p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.405-408.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 204-205.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Feb. 21, 1756; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:44:5. Darlington's Memorials 205.
  - Letter to Jared Eliot, March 14, 1756; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.411-412.) Refers to Franklin. Printed: Darlington, 373-374.
  - Letter to Dr. Garden, March 14, 1756; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:44:6. Darlington's Memorials 392.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 30, 1756; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 3p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.414-416.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 207-208.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 1, 1756; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    London, Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.417-418.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 208-209.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, June 12, 1756; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:45. Darlington's Memorials 209.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 20, 1756; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:95. Darlington's Memorials 210.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1756?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:36.
  - Letter to Thomas François Dalibard, Paris, 1756?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.426.) Refers to Franklin. Printed: Darlington, 370.
  - Letter to Philip Miller, Nov. 3, 1756; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 1:48.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 8, 1756; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:48.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Jan. 22, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:46. Darlington's Memorials 211.
  - Letter to Jared Eliot, Jan. 24, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.432-433.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 374-375.
  - Letter to Jane Colden, Jan. 24, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:44:4. Darlington's Memorials 400.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 1757; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 5p. Bartram Papers 212. Darlington's Memorials 212.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 15, 1757; Miller, Philip, 1691-1771
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 4:80. Darlington's Memorials 380.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 18, 1757; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:96. Darlington's Memorials 214.
  - Letter to Philip Miller, June 20, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:44:3. Darlington's Memorials 380.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 29, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:44:4.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, July 29, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.448-449.) Printed: Darlington, 401-402.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Sept. 25, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:44:7. Darlington's Memorials 215.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Oct. 16, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.452-453.) Botany. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Oct. 16, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.453-454.) Botany. Friendly letter. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 11, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 3p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.454-456.) Friendly letter. Botany. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Dec. 15, 1757; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1757?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:44:3. Note in regard to marraige with Indians.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Jan. 3, 1758; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 12, 1758; Miller, Philip, 1691-1771
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:81. Darlington's Memorials 381.
  - Letter to Philip Miller, June 16, 1758; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:43. Darlington's Memorials 382.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Aug. 28, 1758; Miller, Philip, 1691-1771
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 4:82. Darlington's Memorials 388.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 13, 1758; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to Philip Miller, Feb. 18, 1759; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 10, 1759; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed L. 4p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.470-473.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 216-218.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 6, 1759; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:98. Darlington's Memorials 218.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 12, 1759; De Ponthieu, Henry
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:95.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 30, 1759; Miller, Philip, 1691-1771
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 4:83.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 20, 1759; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:99. Darlington's Memorials 219
  - Journal of trip to Virginia with son William, October 13-28, 1759; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:54.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Nov. 10, 1759; Miller, Philip, 1691-1771
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 4:84. Darlington's Memorials 389.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 10, 1760; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:14.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Feb. 20, 1760; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:49.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 25, 1760; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Mill Hill, Typed L. 4p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.491-494.) Botany. Refers to Franklin. Concerning the war.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1760; Bartram, William, 1739-1823
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:73.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 6, 1760; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:16. Darlington's Memorials 223.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, June 24, 1760; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:49. Darlington's Memorials 223.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 20, 1760; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:49.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 23, 1760; Clayton, John, 1686-1773
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:1. Darlington's Memorials 406.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 15, 1760; Templeton, Peter
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:110. Darlington's Memorials 412.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 15, 1760; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:17. Darlington's Memorials 224.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 22, 1760(?); Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.505-506.) Botany. Business. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Oct. 25, 1760; Garden, Alexander, 1730-1791
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:10. Darlington's Memorials 394.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec. 20, 1760; Logan, Martha
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:71. Darlington's Memorials 414.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 11, 1761; St. Clair, John
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:104.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 16, 1761; Lamboll, Thomas
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 4:60.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 20, 1761; Logan, Martha
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:73. Darlington's Memorials 414.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 23, 1761; Garden, Alexander, 1730-1791
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:11. Darlington's Memorials 395.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 25, 1761; Clayton, John, 1694-1773
    Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.516.) Refers to Franklin. Printed: Darlington, 411.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 10, 1761; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:67.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 13, 1761; St. Clair, John
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:106.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 6, 1761; Bartram, William, 1739-1823
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:68.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 7, 1761; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    London, Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.520-521.) Refers to B.Franklin and W.Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 226.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 20, 1761; Bartram, William, 1739-1823
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:69.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 22, 1761; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:53. Darlington's Memorials 227.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 6, 1761; Logan, Martha
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:74.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 12, 1761; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:20. Darlington's Memorials 227.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 12, 1761; Garden, Alexander, 1730-1791
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:12. Darlington's Memorials 396.
  - Letter to William Bartram, June, 1761?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:39.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 16, 1761; De Ponthieu, John
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 19, 1761; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:53. Darlington's Memorials 228.
  - Letter to William Bartram, July, 1761?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:61.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Aug. 1, 1761; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:21. Darlington's Memorials 229.
  - Letter to William Bartram, Sept. 5, 1761; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:51.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Nov. 4, 1761; St. Clair, John
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:107. Darlington's Memorials 418.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 1761; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:55:2. Darlington's Memorials 232.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1761?; Logan, Mary
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:72.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson?, 1761?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:56.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson?, 1761?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:58.
  - Journal of trip?, 1761?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:66.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 3, 1762; Bouquet, Henry, 1719-1765
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:93. Darlington's Memorials 427.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 13, 1762; Logan, Martha
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:76.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 15, 1762; Garden, Alexander, 1730-1791
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:4:1.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 18, 1762; Hopton, Sarah
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:52.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 27, 1762?; St. Clair, John
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:105.
  - Letter to Alexander Garden, March 25, 1762; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:55. Darlington's Memorials 397-8.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 1, 1762; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    London, Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.561.) Refers to Franklin. Printed [Both printed and typed letters contain material the other lacks]; Darlington, 233-234.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 10, 1762; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:60:4. Darlington's Memorials 234.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 22, 1762; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:23. Darlington's Memorials 235.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 11, 1762; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:24. Darlington's Memorials 237.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 25, 1762; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    London, Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.565.) Refers to Franklin. Printed, contains additional material: Darlington, 238-240.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Aug. 15, 1762; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.566-567.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 240.
  - Letter to Dr. Sibthorp, Fall, 1762; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:56. Darlington's Memorials 429.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Oct. 5, 1762; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 3:36. Darlington's Memorials 241.
  - Letter to sons, Moses and William Bartram, Nov. 9, 1762; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Dec. 3, 1762; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:56:2. Darlington's Memorials 242.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec. 10, 1762; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:38. Darlington's Memorials 243.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1762?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:60.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1762?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:58:2.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Jan. 6, 1763; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:59. Darlington's Memorials 244.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 23, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:40. Darlington's Memorials 246.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 11, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:42. Darlington's Memorials 247.
  - Letter to Dr. Solander, April 26, 1763; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:59. Darlington's Memorials 430.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 30, 1763; Lamboll, Thomas
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:61.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 1, 1763; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:59. Darlington's Memorials 248.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 1, 1763; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:55 and 60.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 10, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 3:41. Darlington's Memorials 249.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 8, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    London, Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.597-598.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 250-251.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 15, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.599-600.) Botany. Business. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 20, 1763; De Ponthieu, Henry
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:97.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 28, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 30, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    London, Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.602.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 251.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1763?
    Typed. 2p.Bartram Papers 3:6.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Aug. 4, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:47. Darlington's Memorials 251.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Aug. 8, 1763; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 1:56:3.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Aug. 23, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:48. Darlington's Memorials 253.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Aug. 28, 1763; Gordon, James
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:32.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Sept. 30, 1763; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:56:4. Darlington's Memorials 254.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Oct. 10, 1763; Ord, Thomas
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:93.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Oct. 23, 1763; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.616-617.) Refers to Mrs. Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 255-256.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Nov. 11, 1763; Lamboll, Thomas
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:61. Darlington's Memorials 436.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 11, 1763; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:58:4. Darlington's Memorials 256.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec. 6, 1763; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:49. Darlington's Memorials 257.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 1, 1764; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 3:39. Darlington's Memorials 259.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, March 4, 1764; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.625-626.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 261-262.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 7, 1764; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:50. Darlington's Memorials 262.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 4, 1764; Parsons, J.
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:95.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 17, 1764?; Lamboll, Thomas
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:57.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 21, 1764; Solander, Daniel Charles, 1733-1782
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 10, 1764; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:55.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 1, 1764; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:51. Darlington's Memorials 264.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 8, 1764; Bush, John; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:52.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 30, 1764; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 3:53.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, June 8, 1764; Bartram, John, 1699-1777; Bush, John
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Aug. 19, 1764; Bartram, John,1699-1777
    Typed L. 3p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.641-643.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 265.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 15, 1764; Lamboll, Thomas
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:64. Darlington's Memorials 436.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Sept. 23, 1764; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.645-646.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 266.
  - Letter to John Hope, Edinburgh, Oct. 4, 1764; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.647.) Refers to Franklin. Printed: Darlington, 433-444.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 22, 1764; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.647-648.) Refers to Franklin. Printed in part: Darlington, 267-268.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1764?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; Friendly letter. Botany. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 19, 1765; Hope, John, 1725-1786
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:53. Darlington's Memorials 434.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 9, 1765; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:54. Darlington's Memorials 268.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 1, 1765?; Lamboll, Thomas
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:59.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May, 1765; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed L. 2p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.655-656.) Refers to Franklin. Printed [Both printed and typed letters contain material the other lacks]; Darlington, 269-270.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 1, 1765; Lamboll, Thomas
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:58.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1765?; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:55. Darlington's Memorials 269.
  - Letter to William Bartram, May 19, 1765; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:63. Darlington's Memorials 423.
  - Letter to William Bartram, July 7, 1765; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typoed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:64. Darlington's Memorials 424.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 19, 1765; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:57. Darlington's Memorials 272
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 26, 1766; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:62. Darlington's Memorials 276.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 28, 1766; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typoed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:64. Darlington's Memorials 278.